Mirgahney H. Mohamed

mirgahney | in mmirgahney | mirgahney.com | m.h.mohamed.20@ucl.ac.uk | +44 7849 718391

SUMMARY

I am a UCL PhD candidate in 3D computer vision, focusing on motion, deformation, and generative modelling. My work utilizes advanced deep learning and graphics techniques, including NeRF, 3D Gaussian Splatting, and Diffusion models, to model the 4D world under Prof. Lourdes Agapito's supervision. I also have entrepreneurial experience as co-founder and CEO of Intelligent Analytics, managing AI-driven solutions from planning to client partnerships. This blend of research and business experience helps me develop AI solutions for real challenges.

EXPERIENCE

Google DeepMind

May. 2024 - Dec. 2024

Student Researcher

London, UK

- Led monocular 4D reconstruction and representation learning project using 3D Gaussian Splatting.
- Extended internal open-source system incorporating 3D visualization methods.

Meta

Feb. 2020 – Feb. 2021

AI Resident, Foundational AI Research (FAIR)

Menlo Park, CA US

• Led a navigation project for multi-legged robots utilizing inverse reinforcement learning and vision-based dynamics deep learning models.

Qualcomm AI Research

Jul. 2019 – Feb. 2020

Engineering Intern

Amsterdam, The Netherlands

- Developed and led an open-source project to help diagnose diseases using AI.
- Conducted research applying deep learning in the medical field on portable devices.
- Invented a new loss that preserves neural network equivariance under extreme transformations.

Intelligent Analytics

Mar. 2017 – Sept. 2019

Co-founder & CEO

Khartoum, KH Sudan

- Led the development of text-based analytics solutions and dashboards for customer textual feedback and comments. This project reduced manual work and enabled clients to make quick data-driven decisions.
- Handled strategy, product development, and client partnerships.
- Currently supporting the development of the next solution with cutting-edge LLMs and RAG technologies.

Sudatel

Sept. 2018 – Jun. 2018

Marketing Intelligence Specialist, Sudani

Khartoum, KH Sudan

- Developed predictive machine learning models that analyse complex data and produce actionable insights to enhance customer understanding and user-centric product development.
- Developed social network analysis (SNA) on calling data to identify communities of customers who interact frequently or share characteristics, and examine how these communities relate to ARPU levels and churn rates.
- Identify market trends to inform strategic marketing decisions and support data-driven strategies by providing comprehensive analytical insights.

University College London

Sept. 2020 - Present

Teaching Assistant

London, UK

• Delivered courses including Image Processing, Machine Vision, Introduction to Machine Learning, ML for Domain Adaptation, and ML Seminars.

EDUCATION

University College London (UCL)

London, UK

PhD student, my research focuses on 3D vision, motion, deformation, and generative modeling.

Master of Intelligence Science, African Master of Machine Intelligence (AMMI), Distinction.

Sept. 2020 - present Kigali, Rwanda

African Institute for Mathematical Sciences (AIMS)

Sept. 2018 - Sept 2019

University of Khartoum

Khartoum, Sudan

Bachelor (Hons.) of Statistics and Computer Science, GPA 7.2/10

Sept. 2011 - Dec 2016

Publications & Patents

- Mohamed, Mirgahney and Lourdes Agapito (2024). "DynamicSurf: Dynamic neural RGB-D surface reconstruction with an optimizable feature grid". In: 2024 International Conference on 3D Vision (3DV). IEEE.
- (2022). "GNPM: Geometric-aware Neural Parametric Models". In: 2022 International Conference on 3D Vision (3DV). IEEE.
- MOHAMED, Mirgahney Husham Awadelkareem et al. (Aug. 2021). Data and compute efficient equivariant convolutional networks. US Patent App. 17/170,745.
- Mohamed, Mirgahney, Gabriele Cesa, et al. (2020). "A data and compute efficient design for limited-resources deep learning". In: A14 Developing Countries, ICLR.

Fu, Jie et al. (2019). "Detecting Waterborne Debris with Sim2Real and Randomization". In: AI for Social Good, ICML.

SERVICE

Reviewer Since 2014 – present

- Regular reviewer at ICLR, ICML and NeurIPS.
- Occasional reviewer for ICCV, ECCV, 3DV and AAAI.

ACHIEVEMENTS & AWARDS

Best National Graduation Project in Computer Science award.	Aug. 2017
• National competition for the best graduation research in the field of computer science.	$Khartoum,\ Sudan$
Faculty Award for Second Academic Achievement.	Dec. 2016
	$Khartoum,\ Sudan$
First team prize at the Sudan Universities Programming Contest.	2015
• Award for the top programming team among all Sudanese universities.	Khartoum, Sudan
Professor Eltaher El-ageb Award for Applied Mathematics.	Sept. 2012
• Award given to the student who achieves the highest grades in applied mathematics during their first year.	Khartoum, Sudan
Faculty Award for Best Academic Achievement.	Sept. 2012
	Khartoum, Sudan

SKILLS

Programing Languages: Python, Java, C++, SQL, R.

Machine Learning: PyTorch, Jax, TensorFlow, CUDA, Scikit-learn.